here's one of my favorite Pythagorean
theorem proofs start with a right
triangle with legs of length A and B and
a hypotenuse of C use four rotated
copies to create a c by C Square the
region in the middle is an A minus B by
Aus b square as the side length is equal
to the difference of the leg lengths of
the triangle the area enclosed in this
diagram is c^ s but now we can compute
the area of this diagram by moving
around the shapes inside if we place the
triangles next to each other like this
then we get an interesting shape with
Dimensions listed here but we can then
view this shape as a b by b square next
to an a by a square and therefore the
enclosed area is a 2 + b^ 2 because
these areas are the same we conclude
that a 2 + B2 = c^2 where A and B are
the leg lengths of a right triangle with
hypotenuse C this visual proof can be
attributed to bascara an Indian
mathematician from the 12th century